{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Histidine is degraded to \u03b1-ketoglutarate and is described as a", "opta": "gluco amino acid", "optb": "glucogenic amino acid", "optc": "ketogenic amino acid", "optd": "keto-gluco amino acid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following amino acids is considered as both ketogenic and glucogenic?", "opta": "Valine", "optb": "Tryptophan", "optc": "Lysine", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A glucogenic amino acid is one which is degraded to", "opta": "keto-sugars", "optb": "either acetyl CoA or acetoacetyl CoA", "optc": "pyruvate or citric acid cycle intermediates", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the best described glucogenic amino acid?", "opta": "Lysine", "optb": "Tryptophan", "optc": "Valine", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A person with phenylketonuria cannot convert", "opta": "phenylalanine to tyrosine", "optb": "phenylalanine to isoleucine", "optc": "phenol into ketones", "optd": "phenylalanine to lysine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Oxidative deamination is the conversion of an amino", "opta": "group from an amino acid to a keto acid", "optb": "acid to a carboxylic acid plus ammonia", "optc": "acid to a keto acid plus ammonia", "optd": "group from an amino acid to a carboxylic acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of a transamination process is", "opta": "glutamate = hexanoic acid + NH3", "optb": "aspartate + hexanoic acid = glutamate + oxaloacetate", "optc": "aspartate + \u03b1 ketoglutarate = glutamate + oxaloacetate", "optd": "glutamate = \u03b1-ketoglutarate + NH3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transamination is the process where", "opta": "carboxyl group is transferred from amino acid", "optb": "\u03b1-amino group is removed from the amino acid", "optc": "polymerisation of amino acid takes place", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most toxic compounds is", "opta": "tyrosine", "optb": "phenylpyruvate", "optc": "lysine", "optd": "phenylalanine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A person with phenylketonuria is advised not to consume which of the following products?", "opta": "Glycine containing foods", "optb": "Fat containing food", "optc": "Glucose", "optd": "Aspartame", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tyrosine is degraded to acetoacetyl CoA and fumarate and is described as a", "opta": "glucogenic amino acid", "optb": "ketogenic amino acid", "optc": "ketogenic and glucogenic amino acid", "optd": "keto-gluco amino acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transaminase enzymes are present in", "opta": "liver", "optb": "pancreas", "optc": "intestine", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A person with phenylketonuria will convert", "opta": "phenylalanine to phenylpyruvate", "optb": "phenylalanine to isoleucine", "optc": "phenylpyruvate to phenylalanine", "optd": "tyrosine to phenylalanine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of the oxidative deamination is", "opta": "glutamate = hexanoic acid + NH3", "optb": "aspartate + \u03b1-ketoglutarate = glutamate + oxaloacetate", "optc": "glutamate = \u03b1-ketoglutarate + NH3", "optd": "aspartate + hexanoic acid = glutamate + Oxaloacetate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the normal breakdown of phenylalanine, it is initially degraded to", "opta": "fumarate", "optb": "tyrosine", "optc": "lysine", "optd": "phenylpuruvate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transamination is the transfer of an amino", "opta": "acid to a carboxylic acid plus ammonia", "optb": "group from an amino acid to a keto acid", "optc": "acid to a keto acid plus ammonia", "optd": "group from an amino acid to a carboxylic acid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysine is degraded to acetoacetyl CoA and is described as a", "opta": "ketogenic amino acid", "optb": "glucogenic amino acid", "optc": "keto-gluco amino acid", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A ketogenic amino acid is one which degrades to", "opta": "keto-sugars", "optb": "either acetyl CoA or acetoacetyl CoA", "optc": "pyruvate or citric acid cycle intermediates", "optd": "multiple intermediates including pyruvate or citric acid cycle intermediates and acetyl CoA or acetoacetyl CoA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A best described ketogenic amino acid is", "opta": "lysine", "optb": "tryptophan", "optc": "valine", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A person suffering from phenylketonuria on consumption food containing high phenylalanine may lead to the accumulation of", "opta": "phenylalanine", "optb": "phenylpyruvate", "optc": "tyrosine", "optd": "isoleucine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}